Samed Temiz Android Developer

Samedtemiz99@gmail.com ₹ +90 553 216 77 65

▼ Izmir, Turkiye in LinkedIn: samed-temiz

• Medium: samedtemiz Github: SamedTemiz

PROFILE

I am a recent graduate from the Software Engineering department. I have been actively involved in Android development for about two years, and I aim to advance my career in this field. In addition to the courses I took during my student years, I continuously improve myself with personal projects and adapt to new technologies.

I had a productive internship where I actively participated in assigned tasks. I had the opportunity to work professionally with methodologies like Agile, Scrum, and Jira. During this period, I gained practical experience in project management and software development processes. I succeeded in improving my teamwork, communication, and problem-solving skills. Now, I feel ready to specialize in Android development and continue my career in this field.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2024/02 - 2024/05

Intern Android Developer

Izmir, Turkiye

- Took part in mobile solution projects for asset management systems, field management applications, and operational processes of institutions like ADM/GDZ, BOTAS, ACIBADEM, and İSKİ.
- Managed tasks on Jira using Agile methodology and attended sprint meetings.
- Worked on Android application projects using Java and Kotlin.

2023/06 - 2023/08

Manisa, Turkiye

Intern

Manisa Celal Bayar University

- Created Android mobile applications using Java and Kotlin programming languages.
- I effectively utilized Android Jetpack libraries in the project.
- Saved application data in the cloud with a NoSQL database in Firebase. Retrieved real-time data using the Google Air Quality API.

EDUCATION

2021 – 2024 Software Engineering / Bachelor's Degree Manisa, Turkiye Manisa Celal Bayar University

2018 – 2020 Computer Programming / Associate's Degree

Manisa Celal Bayar University

Second Place

PROJECTS

2024/04 - present

Athentis Mobile / BilgiYön

Android Mobile Application

- I'm refactoring the existing Java project with Kotlin.
- Developing an application that sends location data to a service at regular intervals.
- Using modern architectures such as <u>Flow</u>, <u>Material3 Design</u>, <u>LiveData</u>, <u>MVVM</u>, and <u>Single Activity</u> to refactor the code.

2023/09 - present

SigmaWords 🖸

Android Mobile Application

- I developed an English vocabulary learning application project with the Sigma methodology.
- This project follows the MVVM Single Activity design pattern.
- It utilizes technologies such as <u>Jetpack Compose</u>, <u>Hilt</u>, <u>Coroutines</u>, <u>LiveData</u>, <u>Firebase</u> (Firestore/Authentication), <u>Room Database</u>, and <u>Retrofit</u>.

2023/06 - 2023/09

FitLife 🛮

Android Mobile Application

- I developed an application that displays the air quality in a region with support for Google Air Quality API.
- The application also features functionalities such as daily recipe suggestions, BMI calculation, and daily calorie needs calculation.

CERTIFICATES

- Advanced Android Mobile Application 🖸
- Android Mobile Application Course: Kotlin&Java 🛭

• Mobile App With Kotlin Pathway ☑

• Java Basic 🗷

REFERENCES

Mustafa DANABAŞI, *Software Development Manager*, BilgiYön Yazılım Danışmanlık Ltd. mustafa.danabasi@gmail.com, +90 555 418 52 50

Atanur Serkan ELMASOĞLU, *Co-Founder*, Forestall Security +90 535 716 91 29